Jorge Betancourt

715 Techwood Drive • Atlanta, Georgia 30332 • 305-205-3266 • jbetancourt@gatech.edu

Computer Science Student and Researcher

Enthusiastic and creative computer science student with an interest in a range of subjects from electronic media to the applications of
computer science to the medical field. Strong believer in that time spent not learning new material is time wasted. Ability to apply
ingenuity, communication skills, and patience to the any goals and tasks. Areas of expertise include:

Agile development	Collaboration	Creative Problem Solving
Responding quickly to	Written/ verbal	Design Concepts
change	communication	

EDUCATION

GEORGIA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY

Atlanta, Georgia August 2016 - Present

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science (2020)

Concentrations: Media and Intelligence

GPA: 3.34

EXPERIENCE

UNIVERSITY OF MIAMI

Miami, Florida

Intern / Department of Physics

June 2014- August 2015

- Assisted in the assembly of a rocket with the task of analyzing an X-ray hot bubble in our solar system
- Designed and coded systems that produced UV resistant films to be placed on the rocket
- Researched and ordered components to be used in the manufacturing of UV resistant films

SELF-EMPLOYED Miami, Florida **Tutor** June 2016- August 2016

Led students in one-on-one tutoring sessions in high-school level mathematics

Taught students problem-solving strategies and critical thinking skills

LUCILLE'S LOVING CARE

Miami Gardens, Florida June 2014- August 2016

Volunteer

- Prepared and served food for mentally ill residents in a group home Organized a group of students to participate in the volunteer group
- Stimulated residents by engaging them in conversation and activities

<u>ACTIVITIES and ORGANIZATIONS</u>

VGDev (vgdev.gtorg.gatech.edu/games)

2016-present

- Design original games in small teams by combining the work of many disciplines including programming and level design
- Learn about the game development process, time management, and how to maintain scope throughout development
- Reviewed level designs to ensure cohesive gameplay and designed levels (Now You See Me, Mount Coldfeather) to be used in the final product of YeggQuest

Robotic Human Augmentation (vip.gatech.edu/teams/robotic-human-augmentation)

2017-present

- Assist individuals with walking disabilities through the development of robotic prostheses and exoskeletons
- Develop software for embedded systems used during the rehabilitation process of patients

Affiliations: Georgia Tech Student Alumni Association, Georgia Tech Society of Hispanic Professional Engineers

Leadership: JROTC - Command Master Chief 2015-2016

SKILLS

Software: Java, Python, C#

Technology: Adobe Photoshop, Unity, Arduino, Bootstrap

Languages: English (native), Spanish (native)